When did you last write a letter?
你上一次写信是什么时候？
Properly write one – by hand?
规规矩矩的用手写的那种信？
In a digital world, where sending a text or email is far more convenient than using snail mail, is the writing on the wall for traditional pen and paper?
在这个数字时代，发信息或邮件远比寄平信方便得多，传统的纸笔书写是否已经穷途末路了呢？
Well, some people claim that writing still has many benefits, so maybe it’s not time to ditch your ballpoint or fountain pen yet.
其实，有些人认为手写依然益处良多，所以或许现在还不是扔掉圆珠笔或钢笔的时候。
These days, when people request things in writing, a typed, electronic document will be accepted.
如今，当人们要求提供书面材料时，打印的电子文档也是可以被接受的。
Doing this on a computer means it could be saved, edited, duplicated and sent via email.
用电脑制作文档，意味着内容可以被保存、编辑、复制，还能通过邮件发送。
But crafting a handwritten document is unique: It requires planning and thought, and, as well as practising your handwriting, it helps you to remember spelling and punctuation.
但手写文档的创作过程是独一无二的：它需要事先构思和思考，而且在练习书写的同时，还能帮助你牢记拼写和标点的用法。
Some experts believe your brain benefits from using old-fashioned pen and paper.
一些专家认为，使用传统的纸笔书写对大脑有益。
This is particularly relevant for students, where typing notes into a laptop is thought to lack the ‘tactile feedback’ to the brain that contact between pen and paper does.
这一点对学生来说尤为重要，因为在笔记本电脑上打字记笔记，缺少了纸笔接触时带给大脑的“触觉反馈”。
BBC Worklife website quotes Hetty Roessingh from the University of Calgary, who says that “taking notes by hand involves cognitive engagement in summarising, paraphrasing, organising, concept and vocabulary mapping.”
英国广播公司职场生活频道援引卡尔加里大学海蒂·罗辛的观点称：“手写笔记需要调动认知参与，包括总结、意译、整理、构建概念和词汇脉络。”
Others agree that handwriting may boost fine motor skills in your hands and fingers.
还有专家认为，手写有助于提升手部和手指的精细运动能力。
There are everyday benefits to using pen and paper too.
纸笔书写在日常生活中也能带来不少便利。
Scribbling notes, shopping lists or messages on the back of an envelope can still be useful, quick and portable.
在信封背面随手记下笔记、购物清单或留言，既实用快捷，又便于携带。
But putting pen to paper in a letter to a friend or loved one can probably have the most impact.
但给朋友或爱人手写一封信，或许能带来最深远的影响。
Pen pal writer Katherine Moller told the BBC: “In a world where it is so easy to hop online to email or to send a fast text, it is so personal and so precious to know someone chose to turn off the virtual world to spend some time with you.”
笔友题材作家凯瑟琳·莫勒在接受BBC采访时说：“在这个轻点鼠标就能发邮件、秒发信息的世界里，知道有人愿意关掉虚拟世界，专门花时间为你提笔写信，这种感觉既私密又珍贵。”
So, while digital skills remain important, don’t write off your pens and pencils yet – especially if your smartphone, tablet or laptop runs out of power!
所以，尽管数字技能依然重要，但请先别急着抛弃手中的钢笔和铅笔——尤其是在你的智能手机、平板电脑或笔记本电脑没电的时候！